Aya Seidemann

Software Developer

aya.seidemann@gmail.com (512) 293-6721 linkedin.com/in/aya-seidemann github.com/ayaseidemann

PROFILE

I am a positive and focused Software Developer with years of management work experience and a math background. Having always been a lover of logic, coding, and collaboration, I have transitioned to being an attentive and enthusiastic Software Developer and eager learner. I look forward to combining my attention to detail and determination with my software implementation work experience to be an effective and nuanced developer.

SKILLS

JavaScript, ReactJS, HTML, CSS, SASS, Node.js, TypeScript, Express, DOM APIs, Web APIs, GitHub, Python, MySQL, Socket.IO, Heroku

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Web Development Diploma

July 2022 - September 2022, Vancouver, CA

The University of Texas | Bachelors in Math, Bachelors in Theatre

August 2012 - May 2016, Austin, TX, USA

- Recipient of two Endowed Presidential Scholarships for academic excellence
- Recipient of the National Trust Segal Education Award for 500+ hours of volunteer work

EXPERIENCE

Program Coordinator / Volunteer Liaison | Madison Metropolitan School District and United Way of Dane County

August 2019 - August 2021, Madison, WI, USA

- Successfully ran Achievement Connections, a math tutoring and mentorship program for over 80 students at two public high schools by utilizing organizational and problem-solving skills
- Directed teams of 50+ staff and volunteers to create inclusive tutoring centers for students from low-income families through fostering connections and being resourceful
- Planned and executed a curriculum overhaul to improve the program's support for students by creating a task force, leading research, and collaborating within a cross-functional team
- Liaised between over 150 students, tutors, and school staff to individualize support for each student through skillful oral and written communication

Software Implementation Project Manager | Epic Systems

August 2016 - January 2019, Madison, WI, USA

- Designed and implemented new medical billing software across 3 health network clients by guiding decision making and analyzing current-state data in a fast-paced and dynamic project space
- Configured bespoke software packages focused on usability for each individual client using analytical thinking and thorough testing
- Assured smoother transition to new software by developing training materials for 80+ users and communication strategies with attention to detail

PROJECTS

Full Stack Developer | SudoTwo!

September 2022, BrainStation Capstone

• Built mobile-first multiplayer and multi-room sudoku game site using Socket.IO, React, JavaScript, Express, HTML, and CSS

Developer | Telus Optik Bundles

September 2022, BrainStation Industry Project Hackathon

 Won Hackathon by developing new TV channel bundling site for Telus through collaborating with a design team in a 24 hour Hackathon using React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

Developer, Designer | Music Mood Ring

August 2022, BrainStation Mini-Hackathon

 Won Mini-Hackathon by team programming a site that generates music genres and songs based on user's mood using Web APIs, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS